# Ong Guo Xiang

Email: ong.guoxiang@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/ongguoxiang</u>

Location:SingaporeGithub:https://github.com/gxitePhone:+65 9177 7675Portfolio:https://gxite.github.io

I am currently a Research Assistant at the National University of Singapore, Department of Architecture. Prior to this, I had spent 2 years working as a junior architect in Singapore, taking on both project management and design roles.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Research Assistant**

National University of Singapore

Jul 2019 - Present

Project: Measuring Physical Profile and Use of Park Connector Network with Deep Learning and Multi-Source Multi-Modal Data Analytics

- Set up and maintained the software and hardware environment to perform object and action detections using Machine Learning models.
- Adapted python scripts from an open sourced research on real time action detections to work on large numbers of simultaneous detection on long pre-recorded video files.
- Wrote python scripts to process to the resulting detections for analysis within ArcGIS.
- Responsible for documenting all research related data and methodologies.

# **Architectural Associate**

DCA Architects Pte Ltd

Jun 2017 – Jun 2019

- Worked as a Design Architect in collaboration with local consultant teams in Vietnam for the design of a condominium complex and show gallery in Ho Chi Minh City. Designed auxiliary facilities, facades and the show gallery. Generated building renders and visuals for all client presentations.
- Worked as a Project Architect for 2 Addition and Alteration works.
   Administrated construction contracts, obtained clearances from regulatory agencies, reviewed shop drawings, provided design directions and produced visuals for presentations.
- Worked on developing computational design workflows within Rhinoceros 3D + Grasshopper and Revit + Dynamo. Contributions includes:
  - A simple pipeline to generate customised perforated panels within Rhinoceros 3D.
  - An experimental workflow that enables massing model within Revit to be automatically generated based on inputs from an Excel sheet.

## **SKILLS**

#### CAD & Modelling

Rhinoceros 3D (proficient)
Grasshopper (proficient)
AutoCAD (proficient)
Sketchup (proficient)
Revit (prior exp)
Dynamo (prior exp)

#### **Graphics & Rendering**

Photoshop (proficient)
Illustrator (proficient)
InDesign (proficient)
Lumion (proficient)
Vray (prior exp)

### **Programming Languages**

Python (proficient)
C++ (basic proficiency)
Java (prior exp)

# **LANGUAGES**

English (Professional) Mandarin (Mother Tongue)

# **EDUCATION**

National University of Singapore

- Master of Arts, Architecture (2016-2017)
- Bachelor of Arts (Hons. Distinction), Architecture (2012-2016)